So, Dan, another position defensively
that, you know, we we talked about this
in the off-season that was uh
huge position of need. And
as a former linebacker, both of us
sitting here, former linebackers, we
understand the importance of the
position. And
this move right here in bringing Devin
Lloyd to this team shows me that you
truly identified and understood the
importance of this position because he
was arguably the number one linebacker
on the board. So,
when you watch this film, you break this
down, and you're making the decision,
why Devin Lloyd? So, it's another guy
not only can he play the run, but he's
good in coverage, and he's also a really
good blitzer. So, in terms of paying him
the amount of money that we paid him,
like, you don't want to just pay a
one-dimensional guy. This guy he's not
going to leave the field. He's going to
be able to blitz and disrupt the
quarterback. You're going to be able to
drop him in the zone coverage. He's
going to be able to take away passing
lanes. He's instinctual. Like, he brings
a lot to the table. Not only that, he's
going to be the green dot guy for us.
So, he's going to run the defense. He's
going to lead the defense. Um I feel
like we kind of
missed that a little bit, you know, here
in the past couple years. So, to get
this quality of linebacker, uh it was
huge for us. Oh, man. So, as we get
ready to watch Devin Lloyd, I think one
of the things
when you think about adding a guy to
this team, we had two guys on the
outside that had five interceptions.
>> Mhm. And now we adding another guy in
the middle that has five interceptions.
It's going to make it extremely
difficult for teams to to pick where
they want to go with the football. And
Devin Lloyd, I feel like is one of those
guys that
he's not just
a linebacker that makes a ton of
tackles. Like you just talked about,
he's a complete player. He can do it
all. And that's what we become so
accustomed to in Carolina, linebackers
that can 100%.
than just tacklers. They they are able
to get after the quarterback. They're
able to take the football away. So,
we're going to jump right into this film
right now and show you guys exactly what
Devin Lloyd brings to the table. And
ironically enough, the first play is
something that he specializes in.
What do you see on this play right here
with him, Dan? Yeah, so I think, you
know, zone drop right here. They're in
cover three, it looks like.
Some Yeah, cover three.
>> Yeah. So, he's, you know, reading the
quarterback's eyes. Again, like, a guy
with height, a guy with length can take
away passing lanes, make big plays.
As we know, these aren't easy Not at
all.
>> linebacker. So, you know, to have that
athleticism to drop into coverage, take
away passing lanes,
uh it's going to be big for us.
Absolutely. And a lot of times you see
linebackers get in this position,
have this same
ability or or
opportunity to finish this play, and
they knock it down.
>> Yeah. Yep. But to see him get his hands
up, get his eyes on the quarterback, get
in position, read and react, that tells
me a lot about this player, man. For
sure. This play right here
was freaking crazy.
Yeah.
This shows you the awareness and the
ability that he has to be able to make a
decision on the fly, but also his
playmaking ability, right?
>> Yeah. And he's got a little running back
>> Yeah, man. His playmaking ability. To
take this 99 yards,
that's not something that's easily done.
I know I've never had the opportunity to
do it. Dan, what about you? No, I'd be
tired right here. I don't know I might
have to sit out that next series, but
yeah, to your point, like, to get as
many playmakers on our defense as you
can, and adding these two guys along,
you know, along with Phillips, it's it's
going to be huge for us. You know, we
got to have playmakers out on the field
if we want to get to where we want to
go. Definitely. For sure. Guys that can
go and and really disrupt the game at
any point because a lot of teams, when
they get down here in this red area, in
particular inside the 10-yard line,
you almost feel like you're going to
come away with points as an offense. And
to be able to go out and set the tone in
this way, to to take the football away
cuz it's the mindset of a defensive
player in this situation is always field
goals or takeaways. You try
>> Game-changing plays, man.
>> try to hold teams to that. And for him
to be able to go out and make a play
like that, it just it shows me that this
is our guy that we needed in this
position. For sure.
Right here.
We just watched him over and over be
able to intercept the football. But now,
what are you seeing on this play? What
did this tell you? Yeah, I think right
here, obviously, like
no linebacker's perfect, and, you know,
good read by him. Obviously,
had a didn't see the guy until the last
second, came underneath. But to like
have the balance and the athleticism to
stay on his feet right here, even though
he's being knocked over by a pretty good
tight end,
>> Yeah. I mean, again, most guys, they're
on their they're on their back right
there, and that's a big play. But him
being so big and physical and athletic,
you know, it allows him to stay on his
feet and finish right there.
>> It did. And and that's one of the
things. And this probably is a play that
he will probably go back and watch and
say, I should have used my hands.
>> Yeah, I for sure.
>> That's one of the things. But like you
just talked about, it just shows you the
athleticism, his ability to be able to
stay up after not utilizing his hands
the right way, and still be able to
finish this tackle. Because we see a lot
of times where guys get bumped out or
knocked off on that particular play, and
it turns into a big play for the other
team.
And this is the thing you love about
him, too, you know, just his ability to
come downhill and be physical at the
point of attack. Taking on a all-pro
Yeah.
>> offensive guard, standing there, still
being able to make the tackle.
Yeah, and again, not trading one for
one. You know, actually coming downhill,
engaging, getting off the block, and
finding the ball. Like, again, as you
know, like
a lot of linebackers, they're not going
to do that. They're going to do their
job. They're going to turn it back or
they're going to spill it or whatever.
But they're actually not going to make
the play. So,
he can do things that that you can't
teach.
>> I listen, I love to see it.
Downhill, aggressive style of play.
Again,
downhill and aggressive. You got to You
got to do it. As a linebacker, we talked
about him using his hands. You can see
it on this particular play.
Utilizing his hands. You talk about his
length. You talk about how how tall he
was,
how long his arms are. Utilize those
things that God has given you to be able
to play this game. And when you ever you
see a player go out and put that on
display at his age, man,
another great pick, man. Good job.
>> Yeah, appreciate it, man. But a lot of
people So, what when you get ready to
break down a contract, right? Let's talk
about this.
>> Yeah. A lot of people had him
in the range of 20 to 22 per year. And
you guys were able to go in and
negotiate
his deal at a great rate for both sides.
>> Mhm. How does What goes into that
process? Like, and I'm pretty sure Devin
had the opportunity to make a decision
on where he wanted to go because I'm
sure a lot of teams wanted him with the
kind of ability that he has. What does
that say
for what you guys were able to do when
you think of when you talk about from a
contract standpoint?
>> Yeah, I mean, he had other options, and
he chose to come here. Um that tells you
a lot about his awareness of like, first
of all, the opportunity to come in here
and be a green dot player. And for us,
he was our top linebacker on the board
in free agency. And, you know, there was
a point where I didn't think we were
going to be able to close the deal and
and get it done with him. But, you know,
I think it's about relationships and,
you know, staying in communication with
the agent, which we did throughout the
process. And we were we were excited. We
were excited as hell cuz we weren't so
sure that it was actually going to
happen. So, to have him in a Carolina
Panther uniform right now, It's great.
Yeah, it's it's exciting.
>> So, let's talk about this play right
here. Go back real So,
on Talked about his ability to blitz and
get after the quarterback. We know how
athletic Josh Allen is. And we see Josh
Allen in this situation run away from a
lot of guys. So,
what this tells me in watching this play
is he
is really good at blitzing, but he has
relentless effort of getting to the ball
carrier. Because now, a lot of guys you
see just stop on that play, especially
with Josh Allen running the football,
thinking that they can't catch him. He
has a ton of belief in his ability, and
he is all out for the team, man. And I
love to see guys make this kind of
effort to get to the get to the ball
carrier.
>> And once you get to know the guy, too,
it makes a lot of sense now. But this
guy is like committed to being a great
player, which is another reason why we,
you know, he was a target for us. Love
it.
Mhm. Unselfish. Unselfish. A lot of
people wouldn't understand what's
happening on this play. But he's
involved in a line game with the
defensive end, right? So, he's going His
job on this play was to pick the tackle.
Great job selling it, making the running
back thinking that he's coming to him.
Last minute, picking the tackle.
Having the size, right? And the
physicality to actually knock a tackle
off balance as well. You know, again, a
lot of linebackers, they can't do that.
>> Contact balance. Being taken taken that
guy on, stand up, and finishing.
>> Yep.
and finishing. Love to see it. So, Dan,
on this play right here, we get to see
him on a fast-flowing play outside.
He's scraping, being patient, you know,
and getting to the ball carrier.
What are you seeing on this play from
him? Yeah, so I think the number one
thing you see from him right here is his
ability, first of all, to diagnose. He
knows the play that's coming. He's
staying square just in case maybe the
the running back cuts it back.
>> Mhm. And then as soon as he knows, "Hey,
that running back's going outside." he
has the speed to chase him down and make
the play. So,
the speed and the range is huge with
this guy against the run.
But, watch this launch point right here.
I want you to freeze this
right here. Watch
how much ground he takes up once he gets
He makes this decision, "I see him. I'm
locked in." Watch how much ground he
cover once he launches.
>> He's hunting right here. Now, let it
play. Look at that. Yeah. Yeah.
You don't see that a lot. You don't get
the opportunity to see that out from a
lot of guys. So, I I absolutely love
watching that on film. I mean, you see
how fast he is reading this here, too,
like tracking the ball carrier, staying
inside out, staying on that hip.
I mean, it's textbook.
>> Yeah. Love to see it. The sky is really
the limit for this defense. I'm looking
forward to seeing what we're going to be
able to do in the draft and how you're
going to close out free agency. So, man,
we appreciate We definitely appreciate
you taking the time to sit with us and
kind of share with our fan base, you
know, what goes into the mindset of
being able to make these decisions. I
mean, I know a a lot of our fan base are
extremely excited about the moves that
we've made so far. I mean, and we didn't
even talk about some of the other guys
that we were able to bring in as well.
So, a lot of lot of added value to this
football team. So, Dan, we appreciate
you. Appreciate you, man.
>> [music]
[music]